Guide to the Burton Kendall Wheeler papers 1910-1972
Montana Historical Society
Burton Kendall Wheeler papers
1910-1972
Montana Historical Society Archives
MC 34
Wheeler, Burton K. (Burton Kendall), 1882-1975
15 linear feet of shelf space
Burton K. Wheeler (1882-1975) was U.S. Senator from Montana from 1923 to 1946. Papers include biographical materials; general correspondence (1910-1972, but primarily 1939-1940); campaign materials (1924-1946); speeches (1923-1959); clippings (1916-1971); transcripts of interviews; drafts of his autobiography; a childhood reminiscence; writings; press releases; printed material of the Senate Interstate Commerce Committee investigation (1936-1942) of the nation's railroads; etc. Subject matter is concentrated on foreign neutrality policy, President Franklin D. Roosevelt's Supreme Court reorganization plan, and monetary policy.
Burton Kendall Wheeler was born February 27, 1882, at Hudson, Massachusetts. After his public schooling and a period of work in the Boston area, Wheeler attended the University of Michigan. He received his law degree in 1905. In October 1905, he settled in Butte, Montana, and began work as a clerk for an established lawyer. The following year, Wheeler went into practice on his own. In 1910, he was elected to serve in the Montana House of Representatives as a Democrat from Silver Bow County. While in the legislature, Wheeler supported the candidacy of Thomas J. Walsh for Senator. For this support, Walsh arranged to have Wheeler appointed U.S. District Attorney for Montana in 1913. He served in this capacity throughout World War I and was the subject of much controversy for his actions in protecting the right of dissent. He resigned in 1918 to avert a possible Walsh defeat.
In 1920, Wheeler was defeated by Joseph M. Dixon in a bitter campaign for governor, but two years later, he was elected U.S. Senator. He held this Senate seat until his defeat in the primary election of 1946. During his Senate career, Wheeler was a constant foe of the "interests" and was chiefly responsible for the exposure and investigation of graft in the Department of Justice (1924-1925). Wheeler was an early supporter of Franklin Roosevelt and the New Deal, and served as chairman of the powerful Senate Interstate Commerce Committee. However, in 1937, Wheeler broke with the administration over Roosevelt's unsuccessful bid to "pack" the Supreme Court. His opposition to Roosevelt was again of major importance as a member of the America First Committee and as a supporter of non-involvement in the European war, which began in 1939. Wheeler, because of his widespread support in the Democratic party, was considered a major contender for the presidential nomination in 1940, until Roosevelt announced for a third term. He was strongly considered as a running mate with Roosevelt that year, but refused to accept the nomination. Wheeler again supported non-involvement in 1945-1946, when he opposed the United Nations and loans to our allies after the war.
After his defeat for reelection to the Senate by Leif Erickson in the 1946 primary, Wheeler retired to private law practice in partnership with his son Edward, in Washington, D.C. Burton K. Wheeler died in 1975, at age 93.
The Wheeler collection consists of thirteen series: General Correspondence (1923-1972), Miscellaneous Correspondence (1924-1956), Campaign Materials (1922-1946), Court Papers (1920, 1924, 1944), Financial Records (1939-1940), Press Releases (1924-1957), Printed Material (1929-1969), Reports (circa 1937), Speeches (1923-1959), Subject Files (1910-1925), Writings (1925-1962), Miscellany (1923-1972), and Clippings (1916-1972).
B.K. Wheeler's General Correspondence concerns the Senate investigation of the Justice Department (1924-1925), neutrality (1939-1942), and other political issues. Correspondents include B.R. Albin, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Charles Evans Hughes, Barclay Craighead, Lee Metcalf, Mike Mansfield, Ed Craney, Elizabeth Wheeler Colman, and constituents. The Miscellaneous Correspondence consists of letters neither to nor from Wheeler, but concern subjects Wheeler was interested in, such as the Daugherty Investigating Committee regarding Japanese fishing near California (1924), the National Committee on Relations with Latin America (1927), and the Sewell Avery-Montgomery Ward controversy (1944).
The Campaign Materials consist of pamphlets, flyers, campaign letters from the Wheeler for President Club and the Wheeler for Senate Club, transcripts of radio broadcasts, and a booklet--"That Man Wheeler of Montana"--published and circulated by the Wheeler for President Club.
The Press Releases, Printed Material, and Speeches all cover a wide variety of topics, such as the Progressive Party, Robert M. LaFollette, Sr., Wheeler's indictment, remonetization of silver, reorganization of the Supreme Court, neutrality, World War II, America's post-war policy, agricultural problems, and railroads. In addition, the Printed Material includes Senate committee reports and hearings transcripts of investigations of the attorney general and corruption in the Justice Department (1924) and of corruption in the railroad industry (1937). The Reports consist of the text, index, and exhibits of "An Answer to the Testimony in Behalf of the President's Plan" to reorganize the Supreme Court.
The Subject Files contain material on the investigations of J.G. Darden (1910-1920), Harry M. Daugherty (1924), and the U.S. Justice Department (1920-1925). There are also files on the Wheeler Defense Committee and Wheeler's indictment. Wheeler's Writings include many of the same topics found in the printed material, press releases, and speeches. In addition, there are early drafts of Wheeler's autobiography, Yankee from the West.
The Miscellany series contains biographical material on Wheeler, notably Dayton Stoddard's manuscript for a Wheeler biography. Also included are transcripts of an oral interview (1961) and Wheeler's voting record (1923-1946). The Clippings series includes scrapbooks of clippings on the LaFollette-Wheeler campaign (1924), reorganization of the Supreme Court (1937), the Detroit Chapter of the America First Committee (1941), and Yankee from the West.
Arranged by series. Some material housed in manuscript volumes. Some material housed in oversize folder in archives map case. See inventory below for more information.
Collection open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
There are ongoing accruals to this collection.
Acquisition information available upon request
Photographs, selected printed material, and artifacts were transferred from this collection to the M.H.S. Photo Archives, Library, and Museum respectively.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Wheeler, Burton K. (Burton Kendall), 1882-1975
Washington (D.c.)--Politics and Government; United States--Politics and Government
Authors; Elections; Investigations--Government; Legislators--United States
Montana; Government and Politics
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection
- General Correspondence
  - W. Horsly Gantt, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
  - William H. Johnson, 1924 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
  - Katherine D. Blake, 1925 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
  - Collier's Weekly, 1925 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
  - Dartmouth College (re admission of son), 1925 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
  - Elizabeth G. Evans, 1925-1926, 1931 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
  - W. Horsley Gantt, 1925 (Box-folder 1 / 7)
  - Mercer G. Johnston (re B.K. Wheeler indictment), 1925-1926 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
  - Henry W. Elliott, 1926 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
  - The Public Ledger (includes articles "What is a Demagogue"); The Survey (includes article "What Has Become of the Pre-War Radical?"), 1926 (Box-folder 1 / 10)
  - Foreign Policy Association (re Mexican land and oil law), 1927 (Box-folder 1 / 11)
  - W. Horsly Gantt, 1927 (Box-folder 1 / 12)
  - G-N (correspondents include George Grose; National Magazine), 1927 (Box-folder 1 / 13)
  - N-P (correspondents include North Dakota voters; Pacific Coast Review, re impressions of Greece), 1928, 1931 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
  - A-F (correspondents include Arthur Babbitt; R.C. Battey; M. Seaton Cohen; Harry L. Day; Denver Trades and Labor Assembly 50th Anniversary Committee; Vin Fortune), 1932 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
  - G-L (correspondents include Robert A. Gilchrist; Frank Hancock; "J.H."; Thomas M. Kehoe; Mrs. H.N. Kennedy; Ernest L. Klein; Lester H. Loble; J.B. Love; Allan S. Lund), 1932 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
  - M-W (correspondents include James J. Miles; Gerald P. Nye; O'Connor for Congress Club; A.D. Sperry; "J.A.S."; Thomas A. Tobin; U.S. Office of Indian Affairs Fort Belknap Agency; Maude Wheeler), 1932 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
  - The Evening Star (Washington, D.C.), 1933 (Box-folder 1 / 18)
  - B. R. Albin, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 1 / 19)
  - James H. Baldwin (includes letters re Baldwin's appointment as district court judge), 1934-1935 (Box-folder 1 / 20)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1935 (Box-folder 1 / 21)
  - B. R. Albin, 1936 (Box-folder 1 / 22)
  - C-W (correspondents include Elizabeth Glendower Evans; Harry B. Hawes; Charles Hosmer; C.B. Horsford; Edward Wheeler), 1936 (Box-folder 1 / 23)
  - A-G (correspondents include Wallace E. Bacheller; Max Bend-Cohen; H.E. Beverage; James Emery Brooks; Mark Childs; M.A. Deas Jr.; Jean Wilson Dewey; M.J. Francill; O. Gunvaldsen), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 24)
  - Charles Evans Hughes, 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 25)
  - H-W (correspondents include Douglas Wilson Johnson; Mrs. George T. Haw; H.W. Nethken; Lowell Wadmond), 1937 (Box-folder 1 / 26)
  - B. R. Albin, 1938 (Box-folder 1 / 27)
  - Montana constituents: A-S (includes T.J. Collins; Thomas F. Corbally; Eugene Graf; B.C. Kinman; Jerry O'Connell; M.O. Olsen; Tom Ralston; Ben Stern), 1938 (Box-folder 1 / 28)
  - B-L (correspondents include Bendix Products Corporation; Perry B. Dillman; Arthur Franklin Durand; H.H. Evans; John Gaskill; Mark Gibson; Freeman H. Hubbard Railroad Magazine; Edith Hyatt; R.J. Lewis), 1938 (Box-folder 2 / 1)
  - M-W (correspondents include Edward C. Maguire; H.W. Nethren; Joseph W. Rebholz; A.J. Ribe; H.S. Sackett; Anna C. Wood), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
  - B. R. Albin, 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 3)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 4)
  - Wheeler Family, 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 5)
  - Montana constituents: A-D (include Joe Bosone; J. Burke Clements; Thomas F. Corbally; Barclay Craighead; Ed Craney), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 6)
  - Montana constituents: F-H (include Frank Finnegan; S.C. Ford; P.L. Grantham; Leverne Hamilton; Helena Trades and Labor Assembly; Mike Holland; Fred G. Huntington; W.C. Husband), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 7)
  - Montana constituents: J-M (include Frank T. Kelsey; Elizabeth V. Kennedy; H.R. Kester, Miles City Star; A.F. Lamey, Democratic State Central Committee; Norman LeFever; E.G. Leipheimer; J.B. Lowe; Harry McGregor; E.M. Mestad; R.R. Mowry), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 8)
  - Montana constituents: N (include John W. Nelson; G.A. Norris; H. Norskog), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 9)
  - Montana constituents: O-S (include James F. O'Connor; John C. O'Grady; Lewis Penwell; E.L. Shields; Pat C. Sullivan; E.E. Sweitzer; Lloyd W. Swords), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 10)
  - Montana constituents: T-W (include Earl Talbott; O.S. Warden, Great Falls Tribune; Dan Whetstone, Cut Bank Pioneer Press; Sid A. Willis; George A. Wright), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 11)
  - Non-constituents: A-B (include P.M. Abbott; O.J. Arnold; Elmer Benson; W.J. Borland; John F. Byrne), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 12)
  - Non-constituents: C-E (include Joseph E. Cassidy; S. Bayard Colgate; Howard Coonley; Bessie W. Croxdale; John P. Devaney; Wallace Doying, enclosing a biographical sketch of Wheeler; Harry M. Doyle, Hudson, Mass. News-Enterprise; Cyrus S. Eaton), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 13)
  - Non-constituents: F (include Perlie P. Fallon; Louis N. Fehlberg; Edward FitzGerald; Clarence Francis), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 14)
  - Non-constituents: G (include Ray George; Robert L. Glenn; William Green, AFL; Joseph H. Griffin), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 15)
  - Non-constituents: H (include Frederick Brown Harris; Milton W. Harrison; J.N. Haynie; Albert Charles Hyland), 1939 (Box-folder 2 / 16)
  - Non-constituents: J-L (include Mercer T. Johnston; Frank E. Lawrence; Lawrence Lipkin, Young Folks Civic League), 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 1)
  - Non-constituents: M (include Ray McKaig; Lemuel P. Mathews; Harold J. May; Frank Miles, Iowa Legionaire; Julius H. Miner; Maude T. Mitchell; John Moses), 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 2)
  - Non-constituents: N-P (include New York Committee to Keep America Out of War, enclosing radio speech of Rev. F.J. Beckman; Charles H. O'Donnell; James F. O'Kelly, Paul Revere Sentinels, Inc.; Anthony J. O'Malley, Wheeler Homecoming Celebration, Hudson, Mass.; Harry E. Polk, Williston Daily Herald; E.A. Purdy), 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 3)
  - Non-constituents: R-S (include C.A. Robertson; Reid Robinson, International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers; C.C. Rowan; Andrew G. Sathre; Arthur E. Seagrave; Harold M. Sherman; James A. Stone), 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 4)
  - Non-constituents: T-Y (include Sol Taishoff; Charles E. Taylor; Lockwood Thompson; A.J. Thoner; Brice Toole; Walter S. Wheeler; B. Loring Young), 1939 (Box-folder 3 / 5)
  - B. R. Albin, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 6)
  - J. Burke Clements, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 7)
  - Barclay Craighead, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 8)
  - Ed Craney, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 9)
  - Arthur Lamey, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 10)
  - Lee Metcalf, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 11)
  - Mike Mansfield, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 12)
  - Richard Neuberger, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 13)
  - R. Bailey Stortz, 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 14)
  - Montana constituents: A-B (include W.F. Aldrich; F.L. Anderson; Roy E. Ayers; D.A. Batchoff enclosing statement of Harrison Freebourn about his persecution by Anaconda Company; William K. Brown; John E. Byrne), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 15)
  - Montana constituents: C (include Ed Campbell; Pat Carter; E.B. Coolidge; Thomas F. Corbally), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 16)
  - Montana constituents: D (include F.L. Darland; J.C. Darrah), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 17)
  - Montana constituents: E-F (include Willard Fraser; Mearl Fagg; Grace Field; W.F. Flynn, Miles City Star; L.D. French), 1940 (Box-folder 3 / 18)
  - Montana constituents: G-K (include P.E. Geagan; Robert Granger enclosing flyer "Highlights of the Roosevelt Record on Indian Affairs"; Claude B. Gray, Montana Farm Bureau; Leo C. Graybill; Charles D. Greefield; T.J. Hocking, Glasgow Courier; A.J. Holderman; Mike Holland; Charles E. Holly; T.E. Kamrud; Elizabeth Kennedy), 1940 (Box-folder 4 / 1)
  - Montana constituents: L-M (include John Leahy; Lester H. Loble (enclosing article on founding of Helena airplane mechanics training program; J.B. Love; John A. Lovelace; George N. McCabe; Joe McCabe; Earl McGinnis, Lewistown Democrat-News; C.H. McLeod; Bob Mackie; Pat Murphy), 1940 (Box-folder 4 / 2)
  - Montana constituents: N-R (include John W. Nelson; Albert J. Partoll; Margaret Patterson; Lewis Penwell; Peter Rorvick), 1940 (Box-folder 4 / 3)
  - Montana constituents: S-V (include O.H.P. Shelley, Red Lodge Picket-Journal; Lewis Spaulding, Townsend News and Comments; Tom Stout, Lewistown Democrat-News; A.J. Stuart; E.E. Sweitzer; Amanda O. Swift), 1940 (Box-folder 4 / 4)
  - Montana constituents: W-Z (include O.S. Warden, Great Falls Tribune; Sam B. Winn), 1940 (Box-folder 4 / 5)
  - Non-constituents: A (include P.M. Abbott; H.C. Alderson; O.K. Armstrong enclosing article from NY Journal-American), 1940 (Box-folder 4 / 6)
  - Non-constituents: B (include William L. Bay; Brancko Bechir; David L. Behncke, Air Line Pilots Assn.; Robert Bendiner The Nation re article on Wheeler; Arthur L. Boreman Dry Goods Journal; Rolland Bradley; Martin O. Brandon; J.G. Bruce, Idaho Public Utilities Commission; Charles C. Buck; J.W. Buckwelter), 1940 (Box-folder 4 / 7)
  - Non-constituents: C (include William J. Clark; Ed P. Cleary; A.B. Cochran; Thomas E. Cooper; W.F. Cooper; Howard Costigan), 1940 (Box-folder 4 / 8)
  - Non-constituents: D (include Kenneth C. Davis; Vincent A. Day; Prescott Dennett; R.W. Digges; C.C. Dill; E.Z. Dimitman, Philadelphia Inquirer; Manuel Dittenheimer), 1940 (Box-folder 5 / 1)
  - Non-constituents: E-F (include George Eyrich; William L. Fitzgerald; Margaret A. Flanagan; Vin Fortune), 1940 (Box-folder 5 / 2)
  - Non-constituents: G (include Linn A.E. Gale, Make Europe Pay War Debts Committee; Phil H. Gallagher; Harry Gambichler; Ralph E. Gates; Arthur M. Geary; Ben S. Gellenbeck; B.M. Gentry; Ray George), 1940 (Box-folder 5 / 3)
  - Non-constituents: H (include Louis Bree Harrison; W.E. Hassler, Washington State Democrat; Edward E. Henry; Charles J. Hitchcock; Roy W. Howard, Scripps-Howard Newspapers), 1940 (Box-folder 5 / 4)
  - Non-constituents: I-K (include Adolph Igra; George P. Jones; Charles M. Kearney, National Beet Growers Assn.; Edward Keating, Labor; Warren G. Keith; L.M. Kesler), 1940 (Box-folder 5 / 5)
  - Non-constituents: L (include George J. Leary; Ernest K. Lindley), 1940 (Box-folder 5 / 6)
  - Non-constituents: Mc (include Charles A. McCarron; C.B. McCullar, Milledgeville News), 1940 (Box-folder 5 / 7)
  - Non-constituents: M (include Dona Marchand; Edward Marsten; George W. Merkle; James W. Miller, Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers; J. Emerson Miller; J. Merancy Murphy), 1940 (Box-folder 6 / 1)
  - Non-constituents: N-O (include Willard J. Nash; Lawrence E. Nelson, enclosing paper on legality of third term; Norman C. Norman; Eugene P. O'Brien, Albany County Commissioner, Pennsylvania; Carl D. Oppenheimer, enclosing radio talks on Wheeler), 1940 (Box-folder 6 / 2)
  - Non-constituents: P-R (include Samuel B. Pettengill, enclosing a legislative newsletter re third term issue; Harold Putnam, Boston Globe; Adolphus Ragan; Calvin M. Roberts; Frank A. Roberts; C.A. Robertson; D.B. Robertson, Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen; Reid Robinson, International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers; C.C. Rowan), 1940 (Box-folder 6 / 3)
  - Non-constituents: S-V (include Fred H. Schomburg; Elizabeth Scott; E.C. Scoyen; Arthur E. Seagrave; John W. Smith re farm situation in Colorado; Clyde H. Tavenner, aide to Congressman A.J. Sabath; M.W. Thatcher, Farmers Union Grain Terminal Association; Francis E. Townsend), 1940 (Box-folder 6 / 4)
  - Non-constituents: W (include E. Welsh; William Allen White; A.F. Whitney, Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen; Richard W. Wilson), 1940 (Box-folder 6 / 5)
  - C-W (correspondents include Columbia Broadcasting System; Detroit News WWJ re Wheeler radio speech; Frank Evans re Non-Sectarian Anti-Nazi League to Champion Human Rights, Inc.; "Hutch" re Sen. Murray; Gerald Jones; J.J. Kindscher), 1941-1943 (Box-folder 6 / 6)
  - A-H (correspondents include Arthur M. Anderson; William J.H. Boetcher; R.L. Frazier, re Under Cover by John Roy Carlson, a.k.a. Avedis Derounian; Milton W. Harrison), 1944 (Box-folder 6 / 7)
  - K-Y (correspondents include Mrs. S. Franklin Pierce enclosing flyer on Under Cover; Sam Swain re Under Cover), 1944 (Box-folder 6 / 8)
  - Elizabeth Wheeler Colman, 1945 (Box-folder 6 / 9)
  - C (correspondents include J. Burke Clements; R.C. Crays), 1945 (Box-folder 6 / 10)
  - A-V (correspondents include Joe Bauer; Dan Bollich, Treasury Dept. re David George Kin, aka Samuel Roth, and book Plot Against America; Mearl Fagg; James Forrestal; Fred Naegele; Martin Norager; Clarence Hughes; Ricardo Seeber; unidentified), 1946-1947 (Box-folder 6 / 11)
  - A-W (correspondents include E.F. McDonald, Jr.; Felix Frankfurter re old indictment against Wheeler; Dayton Stoddard re book; M.W. Thatcher; Robert G. Athearn), 1951-1959 (Box-folder 7 / 1)
  - Ed Craney, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 7 / 2)
  - Elizabeth Wheeler Colman, 1962 (Box-folder 7 / 3)
  - C-T (mostly re Yankee from the West), 1961-1969 (Box-folder 7 / 4)
  - Ed Craney, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 7 / 5)
  - Montana Historical Society (re the New Deal), 1970 (Box-folder 7 / 6)
  - M-W (correspondents include William C. Sullivan; K. Ross Toole; Edward F. McGrady; Oscar Wheeler), 1971-1972, undated (Box-folder 7 / 7)
  - Crow-Assiniboine Indians (re right to sue in court), undated (Box-folder 7 / 8)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence
  - Daugherty Investigating Committee (re Japanese fishing near California and re Gaston B. Means), 1924 (Box-folder 7 / 9)
  - O. E. Pagan to William J. Donovan (re Gordon Campbell), 1925 (Box-folder 7 / 10)
  - Mercer G. Johnston to Mr. Sherman (re National Committee on Relations with Latin America), 1927 (Box-folder 7 / 11)
  - B. R. Albin and Willard E. Fraser (re B. K. Wheeler and Charles Lindbergh), 1941 (Box-folder 7 / 12)
  - B. R. Albin (re Sewell Avery-Montgomery Ward controversy), 1944 (Box-folder 7 / 13)
  - B. R. Albin and B. Clements, 1945 (Box-folder 7 / 14)
  - Frances Wheeler Sayler (re Wheeler biography), 1951-1956 (Box-folder 7 / 15)
- Campaign Materials
  - B.K. Wheeler senate campaign, 1922 (Box-folder 7 / 16)
  - LaFollette-Wheeler campaign, 1924 (Box-folder 7 / 17)
  - B.K. Wheeler senate campaigns, 1928, 1934 (Box-folder 7 / 18-19)
  - Wheeler for President Club, 1938 (Box-folder 7 / 20)
  - "The Wheeler-for-President Circular", 1940 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Wheeler for President Club, 1940 (Box-folder 7 / 22)
  - B.K. Wheeler senate campaigns, 1940, 1946 (Box-folder 7 / 23-24)
- Court Papers
  - Grossman vs. United States; and Grossman vs. Frank et al. transcript of record, 1920 (Box-folder 7 / 25)
  - United States vs. Means deposition; Charles Weinfeld deposition, 1924 (Box-folder 7 / 26)
  - John J. McGrain vs. Mally S. Daugherty Appellee's briefs, 1924 (Box-folder 7 / 27)
  - United States vs. Joseph McWilliams et al. plea of defendant Eugene Nelson Sanctuary [copy; also includes pamphlet "Roosevelt's Impeachment Blocked by Congressmen"], 1944 (Box-folder 7 / 28)
- Financial Records
  - Wheeler for President Club: paid contributions and list of expenditures, December 1939- July, 1940 (Box-folder 7 / 28)
- Press Releases
  - re Progressive Party; Robert M. LaFollette, Sr.; B.K. Wheeler indictment, 1924-1925 (Box-folder 8 / 1)
  - re prohibition; announcement for re-election; Fordney-McCumber tariff act, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 8 / 2)
  - re remonetization of silver; Democratic National Convention, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 8 / 3)
  - re announcement for re-election; remonetization of silver, 1934, 1936 (Box-folder 8 / 4)
  - re reorganization of Supreme Court; Federal Land Bank interest rates, 1937 (Box-folder 8 / 5)
  - re investigation of railroad finance; arms race; Railway Labor Executives' Association; waste and losses in railroad industry, 1938 (Box-folder 8 / 6)
  - re Felix Frankfurter; reorganization of Federal Communications Commission; investigation of railroads; survey of telegraph industry; President Roosevelt's Reorganization Plan No. 1; Transportation Act (S.2009); Wheeler homecoming, Hudson, Mass.), 1939 (Box-folder 8 / 7)
  - re Wheeler-Rayburn Holding Company Act; Nazi control of American defense industries; profiteering in national defense, 1940 (Box-folder 8 / 8)
  - re investigation of alleged attacks by U.S. Navy on German submarines; Nazi domination of Europe; Anti-Sabotage Act, 1941 (Box-folder 8 / 9)
  - re neglect by railroads of safety devices; legislation for dependent relatives of soldiers killed in action, 1945 (Box-folder 8 / 10)
  - re Burton K. Wheeler Scholarship, Montana State University Law School, 1957 (Box-folder 8 / 11)